<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MAPS Workshop]]></title><description><![CDATA[A MAPS workshop for MetLife users.]]></description><link>https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 07:36:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[MAPS Exercise #2]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this exercise, we will explore the editing tools available in the  Story Map Journal Builder  so that we know how to apply  finishing…]]></description><link>https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//maps-exercise-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//maps-exercise-2/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we will explore the editing tools available in the &lt;strong&gt;Story Map Journal Builder&lt;/strong&gt; so that we know how to apply &lt;strong&gt;finishing&lt;/strong&gt; touches to our Plat Packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Opening a Plat Package for editing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to open a Plat Package (specifically the &lt;strong&gt;Story Map Journal&lt;/strong&gt;) for &lt;strong&gt;finishing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;From Plat Builder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary way to open the Plat Package for &lt;strong&gt;finishing&lt;/strong&gt; is from the Plat Builder dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder homepage&lt;/strong&gt; and click the package you want to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the package details page, click the dropdown arrow next to &lt;strong&gt;View Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; and click &lt;strong&gt;Edit Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that you can also click &lt;strong&gt;View Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;, then switch to edit mode once you’re there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;From MAPS - My Content&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are &lt;strong&gt;finishing&lt;/strong&gt; a Plat Package, you are editing the underlying &lt;strong&gt;Story Map Journal&lt;/strong&gt;. Story Map Journals are a type of &lt;strong&gt;Web Mapping Application&lt;/strong&gt; in MAPS. Knowing that, it shouldn’t surprise you that you can also access that item from the &lt;strong&gt;My Content&lt;/strong&gt; page in MAPS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the My Content page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open the folder that corresponds to the Plat Package you wish to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Web Mapping Application&lt;/strong&gt;. It should have &lt;strong&gt;Storymap&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of the name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will take you to the &lt;strong&gt;Item Details page&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Configure App&lt;/strong&gt; to begin editing the item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whichever of these two methods you choose — the end result should be the same. You should now have your Plat Package open in edit mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Editing the Plat Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have our Plat Package open for editing, there are quite a lot of tools at our disposal. Plat Builder has done the vast majority of the work for us — building the content (on the left side of the page) and maps (on the right side) that make up our package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll only cover the basic workflow to &lt;strong&gt;finish&lt;/strong&gt; a Plat Package in this exercise, but if you’re interested in the other &lt;strong&gt;finishing options&lt;/strong&gt;, you should check out the links at the end of this section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Package Overview&lt;/strong&gt; section, click the &lt;strong&gt;pencil icon&lt;/strong&gt; between the content area and the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace the ”…” after &lt;strong&gt;Related Loans&lt;/strong&gt; with any related loans. If there are none, replace it with “N/A”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any &lt;strong&gt;notes that apply to the package as a whole&lt;/strong&gt;, you can enter them after the tracts table in this section. There are also placeholders for notes in some of the individual sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scroll down (or click the down arrow on the left side of the app) to move to the &lt;strong&gt;Property Overview&lt;/strong&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;pencil icon&lt;/strong&gt; between the content area and the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace the “Add custom content here!” text inside the box with your notes for this tract. If you don’t wish to includes notes, you can simply delete the box and the “More Notes:” label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue through your package, making notes on subsequent sections as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your changes, click &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt; in the top right corner of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other editing tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about the additional editing tools on this page, check out these links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://storymaps.arcgis.com/en/app-list/map-journal/tutorial/&quot;&gt;Story Map Journal Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://storymaps.arcgis.com/en/faq/#category5&quot;&gt;Story Map Journal FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.arcgis.com/en/projects/get-started-with-story-maps/lessons/create-a-story-map-journal.htm&quot;&gt;Get Started with Story Maps (lesson)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remember…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is &lt;strong&gt;very important to remember that edits made while finishing will be overwritten if you Refresh this Plat Package!&lt;/strong&gt;. This is necessary since Plat Builder reinserts REIOS data when you request a refresh of a package. This is why we refer to the types of edits made in this exercise as &lt;strong&gt;finishing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[MAPS Exercise #1]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this exercise, we will explore the  MAPS interface  so that we are comfortable navigating the website to find what we need. Here are some…]]></description><link>https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//maps-exercise-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//maps-exercise-1/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we will explore the &lt;strong&gt;MAPS interface&lt;/strong&gt; so that we are comfortable navigating the website to find what we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some links to useful Esri documentation as we go through this section. Remember that these documentation pages are generic to &lt;strong&gt;ArcGIS Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://enterprise.arcgis.com/en/portal/10.5/use/get-started-portal.htm&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://enterprise.arcgis.com/en/portal/10.5/use/search.htm&quot;&gt;Use Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://enterprise.arcgis.com/en/portal/10.5/use/groups.htm&quot;&gt;What is a Group?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;MAPS Homepage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metlifeag-stage.esriemcs.com&quot;&gt;MAPS Homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can think of this as the landing page for all things MAPS and Plat Builder. If you’re going to bookmark only one page - this is it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, you can launch &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;REIOS&lt;/strong&gt;. It is worth noting that you can launch the &lt;strong&gt;My Stories&lt;/strong&gt; page from here as well — for now know that this is an advanced feature, and isn’t necessary for platting (but might be fun to explore another time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Sign In&lt;/strong&gt; and enter your MAPS username and password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will see the homepage again, but this time notice the new links in the navigation bar at the top of the page. You are now logged in to MAPS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;User Profile Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click your username at the top of the page, then click &lt;strong&gt;My Profile&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are now on your &lt;strong&gt;User Profile&lt;/strong&gt; page. From here you can edit your profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Edit Profile&lt;/strong&gt;, then &lt;strong&gt;click the blank thumbnail picture&lt;/strong&gt; and upload a photo (it doesn’t have to be you if you’d prefer not to, but having something here helps with recognition as other users are interacting with the things you’ll create).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️  If you’d prefer to leave the photo blank — thats ok too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify the rest of your information is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to enter a security question/answer (in case you forget your password), go ahead and do that now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your profile settings, click &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;My Content&lt;/strong&gt; page is where you will manage all the content you will create in MAPS. Think of it like a file explorer, but a little more simple - only one level of folders is allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;My Content&lt;/strong&gt; in the navigation bar at the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first come to the &lt;strong&gt;My Content&lt;/strong&gt; page, you will see your &lt;strong&gt;Home folder&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’ve gone through the &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder Exercises&lt;/strong&gt;, you should see some additional folders listed on the left of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ℹ️  The content created as part of a &lt;strong&gt;Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; is always placed into a folder that is prefixed with “Plat” followed by the name of the package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a “Plat-” folder, click it to view its contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gone through the Plat Builder Exercises, you’ll remember that &lt;strong&gt;Plat Packages are made up of three items — a webmap, a storymap, and a feature layer&lt;/strong&gt;. You should see those three items in your “Plat-” folder now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ℹ️  Note that there are some cases where a Plat Package &lt;em&gt;does not include a feature layer&lt;/em&gt;, so if you don’t see one, don’t worry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at each of the items in this folder, you can see the &lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Modified&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Shared&lt;/strong&gt; properties of each item. These properties may come in handy if you are troubleshooting an issue with your package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re familiar with &lt;strong&gt;My Content&lt;/strong&gt;, let’s see how we can discover &lt;strong&gt;content published by other people&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️  Remember that if you are simply searching for a Plat Package, you should do that from the &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;MAPS Search&lt;/strong&gt; is helpful when you need to find the underlying items that make up a package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can search for content from any page by typing into the &lt;strong&gt;Search&lt;/strong&gt; in the top right corner of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click in the &lt;strong&gt;Search&lt;/strong&gt; and type &lt;strong&gt;Holly Bluff&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️ A fake Plat Package named Holly Bluff was created for this workshop — if you’re going through this exercise at a later date, its possible it doesn’t exist anymore. In that case just search for a package name you created during the &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder Exercises&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Search Results&lt;/strong&gt; page includes a list of your results along with a few handy ways to sort and filter them. Since this is a more advanced workflow, we won’t spend time going through all these options now, but feel free to poke around on this page for a bit if you’re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wrapping it up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise was pretty loose, and was meant to show you around the MAPS Interface so you feel more comfortable finding what you need, when you need it. Remember that most of the pages we discovered during this exercise are not necessary when you’re platting, but come in very handy when you need to do something advanced or are troubleshooting an issue.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Plat Builder Exercise #3]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this exercise, we will  Create a Plat Package with Tract Sketches  so that we can learn the workflow for  Assigning Tract Sketches  and…]]></description><link>https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//plat-builder-exercise-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//plat-builder-exercise-3/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we will &lt;strong&gt;Create a Plat Package with Tract Sketches&lt;/strong&gt; so that we can learn the workflow for &lt;strong&gt;Assigning Tract Sketches&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Refreshing Plat Packages&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is a Tract Sketch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start, let’s define a &lt;strong&gt;Tract Sketch&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Tract Sketch&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A temporary polygon that is used as a placeholder for a tract that does not yet exist in REIOS. Tract Sketches have a &lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt; so they are easy to remember.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since they are placeholders, sketches are only intended to be used &lt;strong&gt;when you expect a tract to be created in REIOS at a later time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create a new Plat Package with a Sketch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a &lt;strong&gt;New Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder Homepage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have any tracts already listed, go ahead and remove them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Create Tract Sketch&lt;/strong&gt; and use &lt;strong&gt;Draw on Map&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Select CLU&lt;/strong&gt; to create a shape for your sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After clicking &lt;strong&gt;Confirm&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;Draw Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt;, you’ll notice a new dialog asking you to &lt;strong&gt;Name Your Sketch&lt;/strong&gt;. Give your sketch a memorable name and click &lt;strong&gt;Submit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After submitting your sketch, you will see it added to both the map and your tracts list sidebar. Note that &lt;strong&gt;Tract Sketches are pink in color&lt;/strong&gt;, making it easy to differentiate them from tracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try clicking your new sketch on the map. In the popup, you’ll notice that, in addition to the name you gave it, your sketch also remembers &lt;strong&gt;who created it&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;when it was created&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;how many acres it contains&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; to proceed to the &lt;strong&gt;Data Sections&lt;/strong&gt; step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we’ve explored the various &lt;strong&gt;Data Sections&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Editable Layers&lt;/strong&gt; in Exercise #1, we’ll just accept the default sections and not choose any editable layers for this package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚠️ If including a Land Use layer is a part of your typical workflow, go ahead and include that now. Otherwise, its not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; on the next two steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Review and Share&lt;/strong&gt; page, notice that your sketch is listed under &lt;strong&gt;Tracts&lt;/strong&gt; below the map, and has an informational icon next to it. Hover over this icon to see that Plat Builder is alerting you that REIOS information will not be available since you’ve create a tract sketch instead of an actual tract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Review and Share&lt;/strong&gt; page, give your package a name and description. Then &lt;strong&gt;Submit your Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your package has been created, click &lt;strong&gt;Back to Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Plat Builder Dashboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen the Plat Builder dashboard before - its on the homepage we land on when we click the link from MAPS. This page lists all of the Plat Packages that have been created at MetLife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at what this page has to offer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;strong&gt;header&lt;/strong&gt;, we can &lt;strong&gt;Create New Plat&lt;/strong&gt; (which we’ve used a few times now) or &lt;strong&gt;Assign Sketches&lt;/strong&gt; (we’ll talk about this in a moment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the page is dedicated to &lt;strong&gt;listing existing packages&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;allowing you to search them&lt;/strong&gt;. Try playing around with the search options and notice how they filter the list of packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of packages itself is what we want to focus on. You can see the &lt;strong&gt;package name&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;package owner&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;package status&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;creation date&lt;/strong&gt;. Packages are displayed with a warning icon if they are incomplete, and a green check if they are complete. Time for another definition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Plat Package Status&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A Plat Package&apos;s status is determined by whether it contains sketches or not. Since sketches are only placeholders, &lt;strong&gt;a package is considered incomplete if it has any sketches&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Package Details Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the package you created in the first section of this exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are now viewing the &lt;strong&gt;Package Details&lt;/strong&gt; page. This page gives you a review of the tracts/sketches, data sections, and editable layers it contains. Additionally, you can see the package name, who created it, when it was created, and when it was last modified (unless it never has been).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the package is &lt;strong&gt;incomplete&lt;/strong&gt;, you will also see a card prompting you to &lt;strong&gt;Assign Tract Sketches&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, can launch the webmap or view/edit/refresh the package (we’ll talk about these later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;View Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; and look through your package - notice that there is no loan or tract information in it since we haven’t associated any loans or tracts from REIOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve looked over your package, return to the Package Details page for the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Assigning Tract Sketches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s think back on our scenario at this point. We’ve create a plat package using a sketch because we needed to start the package before a tract had been entered into REIOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we’ll imagine a few hours or days have passed, and our tract has been entered into REIOS, and we’re ready to move forward with our package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;🕐 🕒 🕕 🕘 🕛&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, let’s get back to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;strong&gt;Package Details&lt;/strong&gt; page, click &lt;strong&gt;Assign Tract Sketches&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will now see the &lt;strong&gt;Assigner&lt;/strong&gt; page of Plat Builder. This page is dedicated to just one thing: turning sketches into tracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its important to note that you could also come to the &lt;strong&gt;Assigner&lt;/strong&gt; page by clicking the link in the header of the home page. However, &lt;strong&gt;when you come through the Package Details page, the list of sketches is already filtered for you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this, open the Plat Builder home page in a new tab and click &lt;strong&gt;Assign Sketches&lt;/strong&gt;. You will notice that you land on the same page, but this time you’re seeing &lt;strong&gt;every sketch in the system&lt;/strong&gt;. There are some handy search and filter tools above the list of sketches that you can check out now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, you can click sketches on the map, and choose &lt;strong&gt;Select Sketch&lt;/strong&gt; to filter the list. This can be handy if you know where your sketch is, but you’re not sure how to search for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on the assigner page we launched in step 1, click the  &lt;strong&gt;Assign to Tract&lt;/strong&gt; button on your sketch in the left sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll see the familiar &lt;strong&gt;Loan Search&lt;/strong&gt; dialog that we used when we were adding tracts to our package in previous exercises. It works the same here, except our goal is to find the tract we want to assign our sketch to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, we’re going to have to pretend that the tract we are interested in got entered into REIOS in the time since we create our package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a tract that doesn’t have a shape, and click &lt;strong&gt;Assign Sketch&lt;/strong&gt;. Click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; on the confirmation dialog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point, you’ll see a confirmation popup at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Refreshing a Plat Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt;, then click back into the &lt;strong&gt;Package Details&lt;/strong&gt; page for the package we’ve been working with throughout this exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you get back to the Package Details page, you’ll notice a slight difference. The card where we were previously alerted about our unassigned sketch now says &lt;strong&gt;All Tract Sketches Assigned&lt;/strong&gt; and prompts us to &lt;strong&gt;Refresh the Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Refreshing a Plat Package&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Refreshing a Plat Package allows rebuild your package using any updated information. This is primarily useful when you need to pull in new attributes from REIOS, when your tract shapes have changed, or when you have new land use features.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Refresh Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that you can always find this option by clicking the dropdown arrow next to the &lt;strong&gt;View Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll be presented with a confirmation dialog asking if you’re sure you want to refresh your package. It is important to remember that &lt;strong&gt;refreshing a package overwrites changes made using the Map Journal Builder&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re not sure what this means yet - don’t worry, we’re going to dive into that topic in another exercise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt; to refresh your package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the refresh completes, click &lt;strong&gt;View Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You’ve now assigned your sketch to a real tract from REIOS, and your Plat Package has been refreshed to include that loan/tract information.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Plat Builder Exercise #2]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this exercise, we will  Create a typical Plat Package with new tracts  so that we can learn how to assign polygons to tracts that don’t…]]></description><link>https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//plat-builder-exercise-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//plat-builder-exercise-2/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we will &lt;strong&gt;Create a typical Plat Package with new tracts&lt;/strong&gt; so that we can learn how to assign polygons to tracts that don’t already have them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use much of what we learned in the previous exercise, so some of the basic steps may be omitted here. Head back to &lt;a href=&quot;/plat-builder-exercise-1&quot;&gt;Exercise #1&lt;/a&gt; if you need a refresher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start a new Plat Package and add Tracts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a &lt;strong&gt;New Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder Homepage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have any tracts already listed, go ahead and remove them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search for any loan with tracts &lt;strong&gt;which do not have boundaries yet&lt;/strong&gt;. You can tell that a tract does not have a boundary because the thumbnail will be missing (instead of a small map). You will need three tracts for this exercise - they can all be from the same loan, or from different loans. &lt;strong&gt;Add each of these tracts to your package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ℹ️  &lt;em&gt;This step intentionally asks you to find a random loan because we don’t want to all be editing the same loan at the same time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you see a tract with a missing thumbnail, it means &lt;strong&gt;that tract exists in REIOS, but has never been used in MAPS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You now have three tracts in your Plat Package. Notice that, unlike the previous exercise, you cannot move continue yet. This is because you have selected tracts without boundaries — let’s fix that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Add Polygons to Tracts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have identified the tracts we’d like to include in our Plat Package, we need to assign polygons to them. In this section we will learn a few ways to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an overview, there are 3 primary methods for assigning polygons to your tracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draw on Map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select CLU (or Existing Tract Shape)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload Shapefile or KML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Draw a Polygon from scratch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most basic (and least accurate) way to assign a polygon to our tract is by simply drawing it by hand on the map. While this is probably the most basic method, it should also be considered the least desirable option, since using authoritative data (i.e. Shapefiles, KML, or CLUs) will usually result in higher quality Plat Packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Add Polygon&lt;/strong&gt; on the first tract in your list, and choose &lt;strong&gt;Draw on Map&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plat Builder is now in &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Mode&lt;/strong&gt; — you can tell because the &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; is overlaid on top of the map.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you draw your tract, you need to find the place it belongs in. The Search options in Plat Builder can be broken down into 2 categories: &lt;strong&gt;PLSS Township/Range Descriptions&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Places&lt;/strong&gt;. By default, you get results from both of these categories. If you would prefer to only search one category, you can click the dropdown button to the left of the Search and choose your category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Township/Range Descriptions&lt;/strong&gt; are formatted as:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;T(##)(D) R(##)(D), (ST)&lt;/strong&gt;, where (##) is the number (this can be one to three characters), (D) is the cardinal direction, and (ST) is the two-letter state abbreviation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Places&lt;/strong&gt; can include addresses, business names, points of interest, administrative areas, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s assume you already know that this tract exists in the following location: &lt;strong&gt;T14N R31W, NE&lt;/strong&gt;. Enter that T/R description into the &lt;strong&gt;Search&lt;/strong&gt; located at the top of the map. Once you’ve located the T/R, zoom in to any of section besides 16 (we’re going to use that one later).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Let’s have a look at the new tools available in &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Mode&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll notice there are actually two new things overlaid on the map — the &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; at the top, and the &lt;strong&gt;Measurement Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ❗  The &lt;strong&gt;Measurement Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; is purely there to help you as you use the &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt;, so you won’t really interact with it. As you draw shapes over the next few sections, be sure to keep an eye on this toolbar too, it will tell you the &lt;strong&gt;Perimeter&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Area&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;strong&gt;current shape&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;total of all the shapes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  The &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; is how we manipulate polygons on the map. By default, the toolbar is in &lt;strong&gt;selection mode&lt;/strong&gt;, which we’ll cover later — the important tools for this step are: &lt;strong&gt;Rectangle&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Oval&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Polygon&lt;/strong&gt; drawing options. You can use these three drawing options together to sketch the basic shape of your tract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the three drawing options to sketch a shape on the map — try tracing the boundary of something in the satellite imagery. Note that you can draw as many shapes as you want, and they will all be merged into a single shape when you’re done. This technique is very powerful for creating more complex shapes. Don’t worry about your shapes overlapping either, as overlaps will be cleaned up for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is important to note that &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder&lt;/strong&gt; is not designed to be an advanced feature drawing/editing application — this process is intended to allow you to quickly sketch a tract outline. We’ll go over other tools that support advanced drawing capabilities later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are a few more advanced features of the &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; to help you draw more accurately. Let’s try those out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve finished drawing one or more shapes, choose the &lt;strong&gt;Select Tool&lt;/strong&gt; (the mouse arrow) and click your shape to select it. You’ll notice your shape looks a bit different after clicking it — these circles and squares are called &lt;strong&gt;drag handles&lt;/strong&gt;, and they allow you to edit your shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you can simply click inside your shape and drag the whole thing to move it to another location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark gray drag handles appear over &lt;strong&gt;existing vertices&lt;/strong&gt;, and dragging them lets you &lt;strong&gt;move that vertex&lt;/strong&gt;. You can also &lt;strong&gt;right click&lt;/strong&gt; these drag handles, and select &lt;strong&gt;Delete&lt;/strong&gt; to remove that vertex from your shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light gray drag handles appear &lt;strong&gt;between two existing vertices&lt;/strong&gt;, dragging these lets you &lt;strong&gt;add new vertices&lt;/strong&gt; to your shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Square that appears above your shape&lt;/strong&gt; is also a drag handle, dragging this one &lt;strong&gt;rotates&lt;/strong&gt; your shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you want to delete the shape you’ve selected, you can simply press the &lt;strong&gt;delete key&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’re happy with your polygon, click &lt;strong&gt;Confirm&lt;/strong&gt; to save it as the new polygon assigned to your tract. You should see your drawing disappear and get replaced with a labeled tract polygon, and the &lt;strong&gt;Add Polygon&lt;/strong&gt; button will disappear from your tract in the tract list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start with a CLU&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we know how to use the &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt;, let’s give ourselves a little bit of a head start. Plat Builder comes with CLUs that can help with this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Add Polygon&lt;/strong&gt; on the first tract in your list, and choose &lt;strong&gt;Select CLU&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plat Builder is now in &lt;strong&gt;Selection Mode&lt;/strong&gt;. You can tell by the &lt;strong&gt;Selection Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; that is overlaid at the top of the map. If this toolbar is visible, you can select polygons from the map, which will be used as templates later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the &lt;strong&gt;Selection Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt;, you will see CLU features (labeled with their acreage) overlaid on top of the map now, a few things to keep in mind: CLUs don’t exist everywhere, so if you don’t see them, check your location. Also, CLUs won’t display if you’re zoomed too far out, so you may need to zoom in a few times if you’re looking at a really large area on the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select a few CLUs — you’ll have a chance to make edits in the next step. Once you’re happy with your selection, click &lt;strong&gt;Confirm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve confirmed your selection, you’ll notice the &lt;strong&gt;Selection Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; has gone away and been replaced by the &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt;, which we learned about in the previous section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using what we learned about &lt;strong&gt;selecting and editing shapes&lt;/strong&gt; in the previous section, make any edits you think are necessary to convert these CLUs into a tract polygon. One of the most common tasks at this point is to “close off” CLU’s. Often, CLU shapes don’t include roads or other features, and you may prefer to have a contiguous (i.e. no “holes”) shape instead of one that appears carved out in places. Using the technique mentioned in the previous section, you can edit vertices in these adjacent shapes so that they overlap slightly — that way they will full merge together when you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that it’s quite possible you won’t need to make any edits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with the shape of your tract polygon, click &lt;strong&gt;Confirm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that &lt;strong&gt;Use Existing Tract Shape&lt;/strong&gt; behaves exactly like &lt;strong&gt;Select CLU&lt;/strong&gt;, except you are presented with existing tract shapes to select from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upload a Shapefile or KML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗  Download the following Shapefile to use in this section: &lt;a href=&quot;/files/198934.4.zip&quot;&gt;198934.4.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal method for assigning a polygon to a tract is to use a pre-created &lt;strong&gt;Shapefile or KML file&lt;/strong&gt; (KMZ is also supported, its really just a zipped up KML). Shapefiles and KML files are both industry standard formats for geographic data, and are can be used in many different software applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise uses a Shapefile, but the process is the same for a KML or KMZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Add Polygon&lt;/strong&gt; on the first tract in your list, and choose &lt;strong&gt;Upload Shapefile or KML&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Choose File&lt;/strong&gt; and upload &lt;a href=&quot;/files/198934.4.zip&quot;&gt;198934.4.zip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that Shapefiles are actually made up of many files inside a folder. For this reason, you must zip your Shapefiles before uploading them to Plat Builder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you see the green check mark (“Your file checks out!”), click &lt;strong&gt;Upload File&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Shapefile will upload and immediately be added to the map (notice it is in our reserved section 16), and the now familiar &lt;strong&gt;Drawing Mode&lt;/strong&gt; will be activated. From here, you can use the tools and techniques you’ve learned in previous sections to make any edits (if you want) to the shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your tract polygon, click &lt;strong&gt;Confirm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tracts completed  🎉&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have three valid tracts! You’ll notice the &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; button in the &lt;strong&gt;Add Tracts&lt;/strong&gt; sidebar is green again, and we can move forward in the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here on out, you’re welcome to complete your Plat Package if you’d like, but we won’t cover anything different from Exercise #1.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Plat Builder Exercise #1]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this exercise, we will  Create a basic Plat Package  so that we can understand how the basic workflow and tools are used. Start a new…]]></description><link>https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//plat-builder-exercise-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arcgis.github.io/metlife-workshop//plat-builder-exercise-1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we will &lt;strong&gt;Create a basic Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; so that we can understand how the basic workflow and tools are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start a new Plat Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Create New Plat&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Add Tracts to your Plat Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Search Tracts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find loan &lt;strong&gt;192802 - Central States&lt;/strong&gt;, managed by Bradley Hibbert.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try finding this loan using a few different methods, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Investment Manager dropdown to select &lt;strong&gt;Bradley Hibbert&lt;/strong&gt; (you can jump to D by hitting the D key after you have opened the list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type the &lt;strong&gt;Loan ID&lt;/strong&gt; (192802) or &lt;strong&gt;Loan Name&lt;/strong&gt; (Central States) into the search input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the loan and add all tracts in the loan to your Plat Package. Notice that each of these tracts already have boundaries — this means someone has previously worked with these tracts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add the three tracts individually, or by clicking &lt;strong&gt;Add All to Package&lt;/strong&gt; on the loan itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about these tracts, you can click the tract number to view it in REIOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dismiss the Loan Search dialog, then click &lt;strong&gt;All Tracts&lt;/strong&gt; (next to the search input).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should now see the tracts in your Tract List (on the left sidebar), as well as on the map. You can learn more about each tract by clicking the boundary on the map.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your &lt;strong&gt;Tracts&lt;/strong&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; to move to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choose Sections for your Plat Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notice the wizard at the top of the page now shows step 1 (“Tracts”) as complete, and you are now on step 2 (“Data Sections”). You can always see your progress by checking this wizard, and you can move back to previous steps by clicking that step’s name in the wizard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left sidebar now displays Data Sections, and allows us to choose the sections we would like to include in this Plat Package. Notice that &lt;strong&gt;Plat Package Overview&lt;/strong&gt; is not removable — this is a required section for all Plat Packages. The other default section is the &lt;strong&gt;Property Overview&lt;/strong&gt;, but this section is not required, and could be removed if desired. We’ll keep it for now, and we’ll add a few more sections: click &lt;strong&gt;Add Another Section&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see the 6 additional sections which can be included in a Plat Package. Click the following sections to add them to your Plat Package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Done Adding Sections&lt;/strong&gt; to return to the list of sections you’ve chosen to include in this Plat Package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your &lt;strong&gt;Data Sections&lt;/strong&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; to move to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This section allows us to enable additional “layers” for data collection. We’ll choose any &lt;strong&gt;Editable Layers&lt;/strong&gt; we’d like someone to be able to add features to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the checkboxes, choose the following &lt;strong&gt;Editable Layers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buildings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuel Tanks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your &lt;strong&gt;Editable Layers&lt;/strong&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; to move to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review and Submit your Plat Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This section provides us with a chance to review our Plat Package before submitting it. We can see the boundaries on the map along with the &lt;strong&gt;Tracts&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Data Sections&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Editable Layers&lt;/strong&gt; we’ve chosen to include.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Name and Finalize&lt;/strong&gt; section on the right sidebar, enter a &lt;strong&gt;Plat Package Title&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the checkboxes in the &lt;strong&gt;Name and Finalize&lt;/strong&gt; section, choose &lt;strong&gt;Agribusiness&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Loan Management Group (LMG)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that the options for sharing can change based on how your MAPS user account has been configured. If you don’t see the options listed above, you can choose others for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re happy with your &lt;strong&gt;Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;Submit Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⚠️ This step &lt;strong&gt;cannot be undone&lt;/strong&gt;, and once you’ve submitted your Plat Package, certain things are no longer editable. Later, we will discuss what can and cannot be changed after this step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the Plat Package has been built, click &lt;strong&gt;View Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt; to see what you’ve created!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;That’s it!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the end of this exercise. We used the most basic tools to create a &lt;strong&gt;Plat Package&lt;/strong&gt;, and didn’t dive into any advanced workflows yet. Hopefully this gave you a chance to understand the &lt;strong&gt;workflow&lt;/strong&gt; and get more comfortable clicking around &lt;strong&gt;Plat Builder&lt;/strong&gt;. In the next exercises we’ll get into more advanced concepts.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>